A Guide to the Borum-Williams Family Papers, 1836-1913
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Borum-Williams Family Papers, 1836-1913
Library of Virginia
41684
0.45 cubic feet
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 25 January 2005.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Borum and Williams families were residents of Mathews County, Virginia. Sterling Borum was born on 29 October 1809. He married Hannah Williams (1811-1894). Borum died on 15 August 1873. Hannah (Williams) Borum had a brother Samuel Williams (1799-1855) whose son was Benjamin D. Williams (1843-1911).
Scope and Content
Papers, 1836-1913, of the Borum and Williams families of Mathews County, Virginia, including Sterling Borum (1809-1873) and Benjamin D. Williams (1843-1911). The collection contains accounts and receipts, correspondence, deeds, estate papers of Harry Borum, fee bills, insurance papers, a loyalty oath certificate for William B. Armistead, slave bills of sale, and tax tickets and receipts. There is also a small manuscript tax book containing an alphabetical list by surname (A-H) of residents of Mathews County, containing the amount of tax charged for tithes, slaves, and land. The date of the book has not been determined. There are also three ledgers that contain an inventory of houshold items (1912), an oyster account book (1894-1897), and a store ledger which also contains records of Brighton High School (1887-1892).
Insurance Papers are filed in P.P. Oversize Box 103.
Contents List
- Accounts and Receipts, 1836 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Accounts and Receipts, 1840-1849 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Accounts and Receipts, 1850-1859 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Accounts and Receipts, 1860-1869 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Accounts and Receipts, 1870-1879 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Accounts and Receipts, 1880-1889 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Accounts and Receipts, 1890-1899 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Accounts and Receipts, 1900-1909 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Accounts and Receipts, 1910-1919 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Accounts and Receipts, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Advertisement - Ayer's Sarsaparilla (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Bill of Lading, 1874 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1876-1909 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Deeds (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Estate of Harry Borum, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Express Company Receipts, 1884-1886 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Fee Bills (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Land Grants (Abstracts) (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Loyalty Oath Certificate, 1865 (William B. Armistead) (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Promissory Notes (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Relinquishment of Dower, 1869 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Slave Bills of Sale (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Slave Hires (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1857, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1860-1869 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1870-1879 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1880-1889 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1890-1899 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1900-1909 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1910-1919 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Ledger - Inventory of Household Items, 1912 (Box 1)
- Ledger - Oyster Account Book, 1894-1897 (Box 1)
- Ledger - Store Accounts and Brighton High School, 1887-1892 (Box 1)
- Ledger - Tax Book, n.d. (Box 1)